# **Rayan Mohamed**

rmg742637@gmail.com 07469952484

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Currently a student that strives to become a Video Game Developer, I have spent my timecollecting key skills that would benefit any setting. My experience in working with C++ has allowed me to become a competent coder, and my projects that I undertook during sixth form has let me become experienced with game development software such as Unreal Engine, as well as testing software to debug my projects such as Jira, Trello and Hansoft. Using my skills and experience to dedicate myself to any task will prove myself as a valuable asset to the job in which I'll undertake.

## **SKILLS**

- **C++:** coding in C++ includes using SFML to create graphics applications as well as understanding object-oriented programming and implementing mathematics alongside the coding.
- **Blender:** creating games had meant that I needed to use Blender frequently to create 3D models to insert into my games.
- Agile and Scrum: use of Trello to create scrum boards to manage a team to follow strict deadlines for school projects.
- **Unreal Engine 5:** knowledge of the Unreal Engine development pipeline. Creating blueprints and adding code to them to create functionality for games as well as lighting and visual effects for believability within levels of games.
- After Effects / Premiere Pro: having to create a VFX project using both After Effects and Premiere Pro allowed me to gain a moderate understanding of the pipeline used to create these projects.
- **Jira:** testing games in Jira allowed me to write reports on the tests as well as help with the debugging process.

## **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY

**Liverpool John Moores University | 2023 - Present** 

**BSC Computer Games Development** 

Relevant Topics: Introduction to Video Game Studies, Maths and Graphics, Fundamentals of Games Programming

**Relevant Projects:** 

**ASCII Space Invaders:** To become introduced to C++, I was tasked with creating a space invaders clone.

**Level Design:** As a group we were tasked to create two puzzle platformer levels in Unreal Engine 5.

#### **BTEC**

## The Studio School Liverpool | 2021 – 2023

Level 3 National Extended Diploma, Games Animation and VFX | Merit

## **Relevant Projects:**

**Final Year Synoptic Project:** As a group we were tasked with creating a game based on a given brief about Escape. I was the lead programmer, and we created a game that gives the player power-ups every time the player is killed.

#### **GCSE**

## The Academy of St Francis of Assisi | 2016 - 2021

English, Math, Triple Science, Religious Education, Music, Computer Science | 6 – 8

#### **GCSE**

## Al Ghazali School | 2016 - 2020

Quran, Islamic Studies, Arabic GCSEs | C

## **WORK HISTORY**

## Post Office Clerk | July 2021 - November 2023

Part time | Post Office | Liverpool

- Working in a team to deliver post and tally money. This requires extreme concentrationsince the slightest of mistakes could end up being costly to both the customer and the clerk as well.
- Communicating with customers and teammates to help achieve the goals we set ourselves. These goals can consist of hitting the required amount of postage sent orcan be reducing stock on hand to give to the postmen.
- Being able to complete tasks under pressure by myself to complete tasks efficiently. Not only did this
  help me to cope with working under pressure, it also helped in building self-confidence and helped
  me step out of my comfort zone.

## Supply Teacher | September 2019 - July 2020

Work Experience | Al-Ghazali Centre | Liverpool

- Supporting younger kids throughout their education by using effective communication and team-building skills.
- Guided children to become more independent as they progressed through theirlearning.
- Assisted the teacher by helping the children understand the content of the lesson. I also taught lessons to the children which helped to further their knowledge, as well as dedicating myself to supporting them when they needed it.